minted.us 2017-10-01

# General: What is the Minted Privacy Policy?

**Last Updated:** June 9, 2016

 This Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) explains how Minted, LLC ("Minted") handles your personal information we collect when you use our services over the Internet, including the Minted website located at www.minted.com and affiliated domains controlled by Minted (the “Website”).

 Please review this Policy carefully.  By using the Website or any of the services we provide, you agree to the personal data practices explained below.  If you do not agree with these practices, please do not use the Website or otherwise provide us with your personal information. 

 Registration

 We do not require registration in order to browse the Website. You may choose to give us your contact information during registration or at other times. We then may use that information to contact you about the products and services on our site. Registration is required to use certain interactive features such as reviewing products, saving designs, and placing orders. We offer the ability to access Minted by logging in with or connecting via a third party social network or email service, including but not limited to Facebook or Facebook Connect (each, a “Third Party Platform”). If you access the Website via a Third Party Platform we will access and store the information explicitly allowed by such Third Party Platform by their Terms of Service or otherwise, once you allow us to do so, through an interface provided by the Third Party Platform. As we do not have control over the user interface provided by Third Party Platforms, we do not take any responsibility for any changes or problems with the interface or exchange of information provided by any Third Party Platforms.

  By accessing Minted via a Third Party Platform, you grant Minted permission to contact you at the email address associated with your account associated with the Third Party Platform. Members of Minted’s marketing lists will occasionally receive information on our products, services, special sales, and our newsletter. You may opt out from receiving these types of information, and you may unsubscribe at any time by changing the settings in your account profile on the Website.  Among other things, registration allows a user to utilize 'saved design' functionality on the Website. Users may customize a virtually unlimited number of stationery items. The text on these saved designs may contain personal information including addresses, contact information, dates of personal events or any other personal information you provide. This information is only available to the registered user and Minted staff. The registered user also has the ability to 'share their saved designs.' This is available so that a customer can allow other people to view or comment on their saved stationery designs. Minted will provide a link to the invitee to view the saved stationery. Saved designs are not publicly available. The customer may also explicitly choose to share a design on a social network or other publishing mechanism. Any designs or personal information shared on third party services are subject to that service’s terms of use and applicable privacy policies.

  Information Collected

 We collect personal information when you register with us and when you use our services. Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, postal address, email address, or phone number, and that is not otherwise publicly available. We may also collect and store information about other people that you provide to us when you use our services, including without limitation email and mailing addresses of family and friends, and any such information you store is personal information.  When you create a Minted account we ask for information such as your name and email address. When you place an order we ask for a phone number, billing and shipping address, and billing information. By accessing Minted via a Third Party Platform, you authorize Minted to receive certain of your personal information that is available on or through your Third Party Platform account, including, without limitation, your profile information, name, email address, gender, birthday, current city, friends or follower names, your photos, profile picture, privacy settings and certain other information that will be disclosed to you during the login process.  We may also automatically collect certain information about how you access or use the Website and our services including, but not limited to, information about your internet domain address, clickstream information and other electronic markers and identifiers.   We may also collect information through the use of cookies, web beacons and similar technologies and use third-party service providers that may use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to help operate their services.

 We also may receive certain personal information about you from other users when they upload your contact information to their address book, send you correspondence through Minted services including Online Invitations and Wedding Websites or perform other related activities. 

  Children’s Privacy

 We do not intentionally target our site or our services to children, and we will not knowingly collect personal information from children without obtaining prior, verifiable parental consent. We may obtain information about children who are named on invitations or other products, or that is otherwise provided by users. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of 13 and believe he or she has disclosed personally identifiable information to us please contact us at privacy@minted.com.  A parent or guardian of a child under the age of 13 may review and request deletion of such child’s personally identifiable information as well as prohibit the use thereof. 

 Use of Information

 We use your personal information to fulfill your requests for products and services, to improve our services, to customize the advertising and content you see, to share with third parties pursuant to services that we offer to you and to contact you. We may also combine your personal information with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with our partners. By creating an account, purchasing our products or saving a design on the Website, you may be opted into receiving email messages. These messages could include changes to features of our service and additional email messages about our products, services, contests, and promotions that we feel may be of interest to you. If you no longer wish to receive these types of promotional communications from us, you may select the unsubscribe link which is present in each email, you may [contact customer service](http://www.minted.com/help) at any time or you may email privacy@minted.com. Opting out may prevent you from receiving email messages regarding special offers, improvements, or other updates from Minted. If you use Minted, including accessed via a Third Party Platform, to send information to another person, we may store your personal information, and the personal information of any recipient provided by you. We may use that other person’s contact information provided by you to allow him or her to access the information you requested we send. We also use anonymous information, such as that pertaining to web pages viewed, to analyze trends, to track visitors’ use of the Website, to provide a better website experience and to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

 If you submit product designs for sale on the Website, in addition to any other information required to be provided as part of the submission and merchandising process, Minted requires that you provide your first and last name and location and that you agree to having your name displayed to visitors of the Website alongside your designs.  Your product reviews, comments and any other information you make available in public areas of the Website likely will be seen by people and organizations not related to or controlled by Minted.

 We use the information you provide about others in several ways, including (a) to allow people to respond to and comment on your Online Invitations or Wedding Website; (b) to send reminders and other event information; (c) to display your guests’ names and comments to other guests of the same event; (d) to send post-event communications; and (e) to provide other services that you may request.

 From time to time, you may take part in surveys, promotions, contests or sweepstakes. The information we collect from these surveys, promotions, contests and sweepstakes may be matched with individual customer accounts and used by Minted to improve your overall customer experience, and may be shared with select third parties.

 Information Sharing and Disclosure

 Minted will not rent, sell, or share your personal information with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services that you have requested, or unless we have your permission as agreed in this Policy or otherwise.  You may specify an email address for the recipient if you wish for us to send them an email notification 'gift message.' The shipping recipient will not be opted in to any marketing distribution lists without their permission. We may share personal information with contractors or trusted service providers who work with us under confidentiality agreements, for example our printers and online proof rendering service need this information in order to fulfill your order. We may also contract with vendors to help us analyze traffic and usage of our site, communicate with you about offers and services from Minted, and to help us provide better services. These companies will not be provided any independent right to use or share personal information. We may share personal information in order to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. We also may share personal information when we believe it necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law.

 We may share your information with users and guests invited by you to use services that you have requested including without limitation Online Invitations and Wedding Websites.  You may also choose to share your personal information publicly in connection with our services including without limitation Online Invitations and Wedding Websites.    

 We may share your information with other companies (including select data cooperatives) whose products and services you may find useful. These companies may contact you in order to provide you with information about these products and services.  If you prefer that we do not share your name and address as provided in this paragraph, please email us at privacy@minted.com.  It is important to understand that with some companies or online partners, your information must be shared in order to receive services you have requested through the Website.  Opting out of sharing your information for marketing purposes will not prevent your relevant information from being provided to shippers when you order products for delivery or from other sharing for non-marketing purposes. Similarly, this will not prevent us from sharing information as and to the extent it is combined or aggregated (in a non-personally identified manner) or otherwise analyzed by us or our service providers.

 In addition, we may transfer information about you if Minted is acquired by, reorganized or merged with another company or in the event we sell all of the assets associated with one or more of our services.   

  California Privacy Rights

 Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California can obtain certain information about the types of personal information that companies with whom they have an established business relationship have shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes during the proceeding calendar year. In particular, the law provides that companies must inform consumers about the categories of personal information that have been shared with third parties, the names and addresses of those third parties, and examples of the types of services or products marketed by those third parties. To request a copy of the information disclosure provided by Minted pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, please contact us via email at privacy@minted.com or by mail at Minted, 747 Front Street, Suite 200, San Francisco, CA 94111; Attention: Privacy.  Please allow 30 days for a response.

 Do Not Track Notice

 Do Not Track ("DNT") is a preference available in many web browsers which allows you to inform websites you visit that you do not want them collecting information about you. Minted does not respond to DNT signals.  For further details regarding DNT, visit [donottrack.us](http://donottrack.us/).

  Website Cookies

 A cookie is a small data file that your computer downloads from the Website, containing information about you to facilitate interaction with the Website and our services. Cookies make it possible for us to store contents of your shopping cart until you are ready to check out, and to recognize your browser when you visit. By doing this, we can personalize your visits and save you time during checkout. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on the Website. If you reject the cookie, you may still use the Website. However, in order to enjoy the benefits of being a registered user of the Website, your browser must be set to accept cookies. Currently, we do not alter our data collection and use practices in response to Do Not Track signals.

 You can opt-out of being targeted by certain third-party ad-servers and Minted served ads online using the National Advertising Initiative’s Opt-Out Tool, the About Ads Opt-Out Tool, or on TRUSTe’s site.  
When browsing the Website, cookies from other websites (known as ‘third party cookies’), may be placed on your computer and we may also permit third parties to use web beacons and similar technologies. These may be used for to help us better understand how the Website and our services are accessed and used, including for web analytics, placing advertising on those sites in the future or for other purposes. Among other things, advertising may be targeted at you based on the fact that you have visited the Website and is personalized based on your browsing activity.  We do not control the practices of any third-party providers, and this Policy does not cover the use of cookies, web beacons or similar technologies by any third parties.  
If you see one of these advertisements but would prefer to opt-out you can do so using the 'i' icon on the top-right of the advertisement.

 Security

 When our registration or order forms ask you to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted for transmission. When you provide information via these forms, we use SSL encryption and this should be indicated by a ‘lock’ or similar icon in web browsers such Microsoft Internet Explorer, Apple Safari, Google Chrome and Mozilla Firefox.

 Minted has implemented commercially reasonable administrative, technical, and physical security controls that are designed to safeguard personal information.  Notwithstanding the above, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure.

  Users from Outside the USA

 Your personal information will be collected and stored in the United States, and subject to the laws of the United States.If you reside in a country outside the United States, please note that the data protection and privacy laws of the United States may not be as protective as the laws in your country.You are solely responsible for compliance with foreign laws, not Minted, when you provide personal information and use the Website and our services from outside the United States.You agree that the laws of the United States and the State of California will govern the processing of your personal information, including any obligations of security and third party sharing.

  Third Party Sites

 The Website may contain links to or features from other websites. Our Policy only applies to the Website and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other websites. You should check the privacy policies of those sites before providing your personal information to them.

  Access to Your Account Information and Preferences

  You may edit your Minted account information at any time. You can opt in or out from future communications of special offers and new product information, or you can unsubscribe by following instructions contained in the messages you receive or by contacting privacy@minted.com. We may send you certain communications relating to our service, such as service announcements and administrative messages that are considered part of your account membership. We do not permit you to opt-out of receiving those messages.

 Dispute Resolution.

 As this Policy is part of our Terms of Service, any disputes involving you and us that relate to privacy or the use of your information, and that arise out of or are related to this Policy or our services, will be subject to our Terms of Service, including any provisions regarding the limitation of damages and liability, choice of law, and dispute resolution.  Any dispute resolutions proceedings will be conducted only on an individual basis and not in a class or representative action or as a named or unnamed member in a class, consolidated, representative or private attorney general legal action.  Your access and use of the Website signifies your explicit consent to this waiver. 

 Updates to this Privacy Policy

 We reserve the right to update or modify this Policy at any time without prior notice. For this reason, we encourage you to review this Policy whenever you purchase products from us or use the Website so that you may be informed of any updates.  Amendments to this Policy are effective immediately when posted on this Website. Your continued use of the Website after posting of amendments will be deemed your acceptance of the changes to this Policy.

 You can determine when this Policy was last revised by referring to the date it was “Last Updated” above.

 Minted’s prior privacy policy (which can be found [here](http://help.minted.com/articles/General/Legacy-Privacy-Policy)) will continue to be applicable to any customer who became a registered user of Minted prior to June 8, 2016 (each, an “Existing Customer”), provided, however, that this Policy shall apply to any information collected from an Existing Customer who visits the Website on or after June 9, 2016 during a session where such Existing Customer is not logged into the Website if we cannot readily determine that such visitor is an Existing Customer. 

  Questions and Suggestions

 If you have questions about this Policy, then you can contact us at privacy@minted.com or 1-888-828-MINT.
